Hello friends.
In this course we'll start from the basics of algorithmic trading and quantitative finance which is
extracting data I have spent quite a few videos to help you learn how to extract different kinds of
data which includes intraday data daily data monthly data etc. and I've spent a considerable amount of
time in this section because you need to have a number of ways by which you can get data programmatically
into your system.
So we'll be looking at equity data, commodity data, FOREX data and we'll discuss two main ways of getting
data for your program which includes getting data over an API and getting data using web scraping.
We will look at various Python libraries which help you extract this data for free which includes
Panda's data reader, Yahoo Finance, Alpha Vantage and FXCM.
I'll go into more complex examples of extracting data which means data for a number of stocks, data
over choppy internet connection etc..
Right.
So I have spent a considerable amount of time over this section of the course because I think this is very
important and we'll look into both
OHLCV data which you get for stocks which includes open, high, low, close and volume data and fundamental
data which includes data from balance sheet, income statement, cash flow statement.
So we'll then move on to coding technical indicators and performing fundamental analysis using Python.
So in this section I'll help you understand both technical analysis and fundamental analysis and for
technical indicators we will look into fairly popular TIs which include MACD, RSI,
ADX, OBV etc. and you'll understand what these are once we are in that section
we'll also look at the crossovers, slope, signals, momentum, how to translate the working
of a trader just looking at the chart and trading how you can mimic this behavior using
your code etc..
And we'll also discuss how to write programs to perform detailed fundamental analysis of stocks which
will be required for value investing, We will then move on to the business end of the course which will
include building trading strategies and performing back testing.
If you don't know what is back testing don't worry about it.
This is one of the very important parts of checking your code and I would consider it as one of
the most important parts of deploying your algorithmic trading strategy in the real world.
So in this section we will look at how to code trading strategies how to perform back testing using
historical data to test performance of a strategy how to calculate KPI which is extremely important
because you need to have a way to measure how your strategy is performing.
So in this section we will know how to calculate sharpe, sortino, win ratio, CAGR, Volatility
etc.
And we will also look at implementing basic ML trading strategies. This is still a work
in progress but I will definitely include a couple of strategies that have some ML aspect into it.
Then in the final part of the course we'll be using RESTful APIs to build a fully automated trading
setup.
So in this section you will know how you can write the code and then just forget about it.
The code will do your trading - it will extract data,
It will connect to the broker's terminal,
It will parse the data,
It will analyze data,
It will generate trading signal,
It will book trades,
It will cancel trades,
It will move your stop losses etc. So in this last section we will build a fully automated trading
bot which will perform all the steps that a trained human can perform for trading purposes.
And we will be using FXCM which is a very popular broker for fx trading.
we will be using their demo account for testing this live trading and creating this bot.