So as you can figure out this is a course of intermediate level difficulty so it would be great if
you have some Python skills.
Basic Python skills are definitely required without which you will be a bit lost in this course.
So I would urge you to build some level of Python proficiency and when I say Python proficiency
I mean you should be able to understand how to write a function, how to loop through a list,
What are dictionaries etc.
And good to have skills would be you know some familiarity with numpy, pandas, matplotlib, statsmodel
sklearn etc. In the code section of my course where I explain in the video how this
code is functioning I will try to explain everything in the code.
But if you have some familiarity you will be able to pick these videos pick these lessons
way more quickly than if you are a complete novice.
So I would urge you to just brush up your basic Python if you want to extract the most out of this course.
OK.
And some experience in trading is also required because I'll be using stocks, commodity, forex
data etc.
So some familiarity with trading parlance will be very appreciated because I'll be using words like
high, low, candlesticks, stop loss.
I'll explain what these are
But sometimes I may miss it because it's something maybe really basic. For example going long or
going shot etc. So If you have the basic of these trading parlance then that would also be tremendously
helpful. And basic statistics high school level statistics and mathematics is also required for this
course.
So again I will underline that this courses is of intermediate level difficulty.
So I would urge you to just brush up the areas that we think will be required.