This course is for a lot of demographics.
So if you are a trader who want to automate your trading strategies you will be able to benefit the
most from this course.
If you already have your trading strategy and your trading strategies are live in the market,
you are already trading using charts or performing fundamental analysis and if you're looking
for a way to automate your strategy so that you have more time to think about more strategies and think
about more intellectual things then you'll be the demographic that will be most benefited from
this course.
In addition if you are an engineer who wants to build an automated trading station this will also be
very helpful for you.
Our data scientists who love to work with data, live streaming financial data, how to make sense of it?
This course
You will also find this course helpful. And anyone who wants to gain an understanding of trading programmatically
or anyone who is curious should be able to find this course useful.
I would like to underscore that this course is not for high frequency traders.
So a significant part of algorithmic trading deals with high frequency trading which delves in very
low latency kind of trading algorithm where the algorithm is making trading decisions in
milliseconds
So this course doesn't cater to that part of the algorithmic trading
world.
All my strategies that I will discuss in this course will be of medium to high latency.
I just want to make this thing clear at the outset.