This is very important. Because this course is of intermediate level difficulty, you will have
questions when I'm explaining. Both in the overview sections and in the coding sections you will have
problems so do post it in the Q&A section.
I regularly review the Q&A section and provide the answers.
But try to make my life a bit easier.
So write a descriptive post in the Q and A section.
For example if you just say something like I'm getting error so I'll not be able to help.
So if you mention what is it that you're trying to do and what are the steps that you took
and what is the error that you're getting.
If you give me the message in this kind of structured format it would really help me to troubleshoot
your problem and help you provide the solution for that issue.
Okay?
And also I would urge you to spend some time on the Internet trying to find the answer.
And this is one of the most important part by which people learn.
If you're new in the world of coding, if you're starting out, if you're not
an expert in coding etc. You will get into issues you will find errors you will think that you have
hit a wall etc.
However now in the in the age of internet help is available everywhere and forums like Stackoverflow,
github, somewhere someone has already had this problem that you are facing and they have discussed about
it and they have found a solution.
And I'll spend some time trying to explain how to get help over stackoverflow
etc. and how to access documentation of various Python libraries so I'll be really happy if you
are able to pick up this skill at the end of this course of how to seek help from the relevant
forums.
So being able to frame the right questions and search for the relevant information is a very important
skill in the world of programming.
The importance of this aspect cannot be emphasized more so try to get help from
those sources as well.
And you can directly drop me a note on my personal email id
I may take some time to get back to you
but I review every single mail that I get in my personal mailbox so you can utilize this avenue as well
If you have exhausted the previous two avenues and you have not been able to get your answer.
I'm really excited that you have enrolled for this course and I hope that we will be able to
make something awesome.
So let's jump straight into the course.