Hello friends.
Some of you have reached out to me saying that some of the coding Videos tend to be blurry.
Let me assure you that every single video, every single lecture of this course has been created at 1080p
resolution which is high definition.
And there is no reason why any of you should have blurriness the in coding videos or any other videos
for that matter. And Udemy has also assured me that they have enabled something called Adaptive
Streaming which means students should be able to stream
the videos of this course at 1080p resolution.
So let me tell you a couple of things that you should be mindful of when you are streaming any videos
of this course.
When you are streaming a course, if you look at the settings button
by default it is at 720p.
So all you need to do is choose the auto stream.
And that actually.....let me make it full screen.
So when you choose auto.
.
The resolution should become better and should be the one that I actually intended for the students
to see.
But by default it is at 720p.
Actually let me show you how it looks at 720p.
.
So if you see these videos are a bit blurry at 720p
And it may not be very comfortable to view them at 720 so always make sure that you are streaming the
videos especially the coding videos at 1080p
.
And another thing is that some of you may not be able to stream it at 1080p depending on the Internet
connection you have or any bandwidth issues that you may be facing.
So another option is for you to download these lectures especially the coding lectures.
I have made every single video, every single lecture of this course downloadable so you should be
able to download these lectures and then see it offline.
You can have offline viewing privileges as well.
So just wanted to make these things clear.
None of you should have any issue with the blurriness. If you're still having issues with blurriness
reach out to me and I'll make sure that you are not having that issue.
.
So thanks a lot.
Happy learning.