Hello friends before you start on discourse I strongly recommend that you install anacondas by and distribution
anacondas it and distribution is a free and open source Python distribution that has a number of libraries
that will be using in this course Anaconda is used extensively by data scientist by quants by researchers
in different areas like biomedical engineering physics and what not.
So Anaconda is one of the most popular distributions that is used and I can assure you that it would
make your life very easy.
It also has a lot of tools that will help you manage the libraries installing stuff on and starting
stuff and once you start using it you will start appreciating how convenient and easy to use it is right.
So just go to Anaconda right.
And then based on which our operating system you are having I'm assuming most of you will have been
those are Mac OS right.
Just go to whichever OS you have it and then install whatever version that you want.
I would recommend that you go with by three point seven Virgin or R Python 3 virgin and not Python tuition
because I'm using Python 3.
So once you will download right you will get like a file which is close to 500 and be in your download
folder.
Right.
Just double click on it and follow all the default steps.
Just choose all the default options and it will install Anaconda on your system.
OK so I have already installed it so I'm not going to do that but it's fairly straightforward.
So I hope that you'll will be able to do it.
Great.
Once you install it I want you to go to Anaconda prompt.
Right.
Anaconda prompt.
Or you will get it right.
So what is Anaconda prompt and why do we use it.
So you will see that in the scores I'll be asking you to install a number of libraries right.
Different lectures will correspond to different libraries.
Right.
So you will have to install a number of libraries.
And this is how you would install it.
So there are two package managers in Anaconda do popular package managers.
One is Pip and one is Canada.
Right.
So you can install any library using either pip or using the.
So for example if you want to install pandas right you can simply install that library's by running
this command.
Right Pip and bind us are gonna install pandas.
So for example if I ask you in one of my lecture that I will be using life in hands or will be using
cyclone.
Right.
So all you have to do is just search for Pip install life and answer something like that right.
And then you will get a link of what is the actual command that you need to install that particular
library.
Right.
So it's fairly easy it's it's it's such a display to install libraries these days some libraries can
get a bit tricky but I mean I won't really be covering many of those libraries in the schools right
but this is how you install any library.
I'll stop the video here and then the next lecture video will discuss how to create a virtual environment.
And why do we even need a virtual environment.
So I'll see you in the next lecture video.
Thanks a lot.