Hello friends in this lecture video we will create a virtual environment they will perform all the work
related to this particular course.
Now you may ask what on earth is this what you will enlightenment.
So when you installed Anaconda in the previous lecture would you and when you open Anaconda prompt you
will see a base and inherit it.
So that means that Anaconda has created a base environment for you right.
So now which whichever library you want to install right.
It will be installed in the base environment.
Right.
So what can go wrong with that.
So say you are working on different projects one data science project one a conference project right.
One a physics project.
The problem is that if you start a library say six months ago and now you have started working on a
quant finance project and now you want to install another library.
Right.
The problem is that this new library may have a dependence on the previous library that you are already
in start.
Right.
But when you install this new library it will install a newer version.
The latest version of the library that you had in started six months ago.
So the code that you have written six months ago on based on the library that you just installed it
may not work right.
Because whenever new libraries happen function calls keep getting placated or they keep making changes.
That's the problem with open source libraries is that the the new version release your code may not
run.
That's the problem.
So it's always recommended that you create different environments for different projects that you're
working on.
Right.
And creating new virtual environment is a child's play these days.
So just use this command gonna create name or name of the virtual environment.
So let's call it go on top.
You can have whatever name that you want right.
And then you will have to mention which Python do you want to use.
Right.
So by and three point eight I think poisoned by ten point nine has already been released.
But I'll go with Python three point eight because it's a stable vision.
I typically not go with the latest version of Python.
I typically go will with the last stable version.
Right.
It's just a hybrid.
So once we run this command you will see that it's the new what is the current version of and you can
get a newer version I don't really want in your version and as you can see it is telling you that the
following packages will be downloaded if you want to create this virtual environment.
So these are the libraries that will be installed by default.
When you create this new watch will environment right.
So when you will at the end of this you know when we create this virtual environment you would already
have these libraries in the start.
And what are these libraries.
PIP by ten three point eight set up dos askew light like these are some of the basic libraries that
you need to create any watch your environment.
Right.
So I will give it this so I'll just say yes and I'll hit enter and now it will install all these libraries
and the dependencies.
So I am going to follow this lecture with you.
So as you can see all these libraries have been started and your environment has been created.
Hooray.
Congratulations.
You have created a brand new watchful environment.
And you can see that Kaunda is prompting you some of the commands right.
So what it's saying that by default if you open Anaconda prompt it will open in the base environment
right.
All you'll have to do to kind of activate an environment is to run this command gone to activate the
name of the environment.
But before that let me actually show you how you can get the list off all the environments that you
have created in your system right.
That's pretty straightforward.
All you will have to do is run this command right Kaunda info to hyphens and right.
It will tell you all the environments that are installed in your system right.
So I have four environments right.
And most of my work is to finance related so most of my you can see that everything is pretty much dedicated
to the same area.
Right.
So.
So how do you activate the second environment that you've already created.
All you'll have to do is do gonna activate it.
Right.
And million run it you will see that now my environment is one.
So now if you install something right.
So now if you do a pip install or corner install whatever right now that liability will be installed
in the want virtual environment.
Right.
The fullest library that you need to install is the idea.
There are a number of ideas like spider like Jupiter notebook like by John.
Right.
I would strongly recommend you that you install spider.
So one venue downloaded and one you when you installed Anaconda.
Spider this is the icon of spider Idi.
It was already installed in your system in the base environment by default.
Right.
But we won't be able to use that because we have created a new watchful environment.
So we'll have to install spider I.D. as well.
And every time again like I mention just Google how to install a library you watch the come on must
do this pip installed a core nine install rate but because we have created this environment in Canada
I would recommend that install packages using corn right.
So let us see what is
come on Falcon 9 stole spider right.
So if we go to the command that is required right.
So gonna install minus C and a car and a spider.
So let me on this.
So.
So once you have installed your I.D. indicate a spider.
The way to launch it is that once you have activated your watch will environment.
Just type spider and press enter.
Right.
The problem is that for example if I run it I'll get an ETA.
Why.
Because I already have an instance of spider running right.
So it's saying that spider is already running.
So if you have launched the spider IP from any other environment trade so you will have to run this
command spider new instance.
Right.
So if you launch this right if you will run this then a new instance of spider will be launched for
your particular environment.
Great.
So just keep that in mind.
In addition you will have to install mean libraries popular libraries like pandas like pip install Panda.
What else.
No.
So not people being startled when you install pandas anyways.
Right.
Mac block liberate.
So as we will progress to the cause I will tell you which libraries to install.
And please just open your Anaconda prompt enter the virtual environment.
If you have created the virtual environment and then install whatever library are talking about.
Great.
When you are installing a particular library just keep one thing in mind that if you say run corner
installed by another whatever and if you run this particular command it will install the latest was
one of pandas in your system right.
I would strongly urge you that you use the same version of the library that I have used while creating
this particular course.
Why.
Because if you use a different version did like we've discussed before the different version can have
certain changes that will impact the code that I share.
Right.
So if you can troubleshoot that's great but it will save both of us a lot of time.
If you're using the same library version that I use right.
So all you have to do is just use a double equal to and then just provide whichever version I am using
so I'll give you a list of library versions that I have used it would be great if you can install the
same versions when you're installing the library.
You also need to if you want to deactivate this particular environment if you want to come out of this
environment I disclosed this or just do Condor the Activate Kwan right on and it will go back to base.
So we just gonna deactivate
I typically don't use this command like this closer.
Right.
So you see that we have come back to Guan right.
So this is how we create a virtual environment.
If you don't want to create virtual environment that's fine.
Even with the base environment you should be fine.
But if you created that slightly better.
And I would recommend you to create it right.
Because that will help you a while a lot of backward compatibility issues and some other issues that
you may face.
But even if you don't create a virtual environment that's fine.
Right.
So if you have if you're facing any problem pertaining to creating virtual environment posted in the
Q and A section and I'll do my best to resolve it.
Thanks a lot.
I'll see you in the next lecture video.